Lastly, we will look into handling props
It is basically setting properties while advanced skills are needed
to fully understand its detailed techniques
Since it is only necessary in some complicated models
we will set constant properties instead
For example, we use those props and we want them to
take effect in the model
Let's look at the function, the input is 'mdl.Model'
We can see that 'mdl' is 'lib.Model'
Then we can find it from 'model.py' in lib
Inside the class 'Model', there is function call 'handle_props'
It defines how the model handle the props
Therefore, we can define how the model use the props as input
by overriding the function in our model
Here just a brief introduction of handling props
For more details, please check the following video or introduction
This concludes our last step on
building a segregation model based on the template
The detailed steps in this tutorial are mostly general steps
hat can apply to any other easily customizable ABM models
Thanks for watching
please feel free to contact us if you have any questions