We will modify a prototype model (basic model in basic.py)
into a real segregation model
step by step to show that new developers don't have to start from scratch
But before we get started, let me have a brief introduction of segregation model
The goal is to show that people with mild in-group preference towards their own group, could still lead to a highly segregated society
Next let's get into changing the code. I will explain more during the process.
Firstly, let's manage our agent settings like agent names and agent numbers.
Each model will have a parameter called grp_struct which is a dictionary
that contains group agent info either as a default constant
or as a variable mapping to a specified value in [MODEL_NAME].props.json
let's look at the basic_grps:
We can see two keys: blue_grp and red_grp.
Those are the group names that you can customize.
Let's see inside what we have in blue_grp.
The first attribute defines what the agent will do at each turn when the model is running.
What the agent will do is specified in a function called basic_action
We will dig into this function later
The second and third attributes together define the number of agents that we want to have.
mdl.NUM_MBRS_PROP specifies that we are going to read the number of blue agents from the variable num_blue
which is defined in the [MODEL_NAME].props.json
If we fail to get the property value, the fallback method would be to get the value from DEF_BLUE_MBRS constant which we specified in the second attribute
Let's play around a bit to see how the changes in this setting affect the model
You can see the value for num_blue and num_red in props.json file is 2
Change the value for num_blue to 4
Now we see that the default input for the number of blue agents is 4,
while that number for red agents is 2
We can see that the numbers of agents are the default numbers when the model is running
Then we try to give our input for the numbers of agents
Type in 8
The number of blue agents changed to 8
Now we try to remove the 'num_blue' and see the default value DEF_BLUE_MBRS to take effect.
Renaming num_blue to num_green in basci_props.json
Now mdl.NUM_MBRS_PROP fail to get the property value
The the number of agents is the value from DEF_BLUE_MBRS constant which we specified in the second attribute