Next, we will focus on the action of agents
Basically there are mainly two parts of action you need to define in your new model
The agent first surveys the environment
The second is to respond to the result of that survey
So we need to define a function (we call agent_action in ABM system) to show how the agent surveys the environment and its response to the result
In segregation model, the agent first surveys the environment and find the ratio of agents in the same group
We could call a predefined function called neighbor_ratio() to easily get the ratio
Then, we need to define its response to the result of the survey
It is rather simple
If the ratio is no less than its tolerance which means the agent is happy about where it is, it will stay put
If the ratio is less than its tolerance, it will move
We define two helper functions and some default values to make the structure clearer
The first function(get_tolerance) is used to calculate a tolerant number
In this case, we don't assign a uniform tolerance rate for all agents
Instead, we have a default tolerance rate and assign values in the manner of gauss distribution around it to the agents